Guide to the David Plowden Photographs and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1948-2011; Series I; 189; 41.9 linear_feet
  - July 2012 Acquisition
    - Approaching the 98th Meridian. Steele County, North Dakota (GFB-68-2588), 1968 (Box 188)
    - "Bat" Nelson's Barber Shop. Alta Vista, Kansas (591-1692), 1991 (Box 188)
    - Bridgeman Newburgh Ferry Co. on Float Bridge. Newburgh, New York (NBF-1163-508), 1963 (Box 188)
    - Capt. Walter Davis, Superintendent of Marine Operations, F/B Elmira, Erie-Lackawanna Railroad in Pilot House of F/B Elmira. Hoboken, New Jersey (EL-467-297), 1967 (Box 188)
    - Cars Parked in Front of Former Erie Railroad Depot. Tenafly, New Jersey (NJ-1263-???), 1963 (Box 188)
    - Coney's N' More. Fort Dodge, Iowa (304-2226), 2004 (Box 188)
    - Conveyer Dolomite Quarry. Gulliver, Michigan (ISM-190), 1980 (Box 188)
    - Detail, South Approach Span. Yaquina Bay Bridge, Newport, Oregon (GFB-68-2814), 1968 (Box 188)
    - Erie-Lackawanna Railroad, Hoboken Ferries, F/B Pocono (front) and F/B Elmira(right) on Hudson River, en route Barclay Street, New York City. Hoboken, New Jersey (FBDL-1), 1960 (Box 188)
    - Factory Building beside BN-SF Railroad. Burlington, Iowa (804-205), 2004 (Box 188)
    - Farm and Road. Near Clare, Humboldt County, Iowa (611-182), 2011 (Box 188)
    - Farm beside C, 1986 (Box 188)
    - Farm Buildings. North of West Liberty, Cedar County, Iowa (487-481), 1987 (Box 188)
    - Francis Buck. Scott County, Iowa (GP-93), 1971 (Box 188)
    - Gotebo, Oklahoma (969-337), 1969 (Box 188)
    - Grain Elevator. Regan, North Dakota (805-???), 2005 (Box 188)
    - Grain elevator Detail. Manteno, Illinois (281-???), 1981 (Box 188)
    - Grain Elevators in Distance. Mingo, Thomas County, Kansas (610-1121), 2010 (Box 188)
    - Great Northern Railway, extra 3383 [negative]. East Kandiyohi, Minnesota (GN-005), 1956 (Box 188)
    - Levite's Store. Apache, Oklahoma (969-337), 1969 (Box 188)
    - New York Central Railroad Steam Tugs at New Jersey Terminal. Weehawken, New Jersey (ST-NYC-263-001), 1963 (Box 188)
    - North of Deep River, Powshiek County, Iowa (586-???), 1986 (Box 188)
    - NY Central Railroad Steam Tug, NY Central No. 31. Weehawken, New Jersey (NYH-ST-NYC-263-170), 1960 (Box 188)
    - Office, Bohstedt's Feed Mill. Victor, Iowa (586-411), 1986 (Box 188)
    - Planting Beans. North of Deep River, Powshiek County, Iowa (586-313), 1986 (Box 188)
    - Reading Company [Railroad]. Susquehanna River, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania (GFB-469-142), 1969 (Box 188)
    - Section Road. Calhoun County, Iowa (304-1003), 2004 (Box 188)
    - Section Road. Scott County, Iowa (486-122), 1986 (Box 188)
    - Section Road. Stanley County, South Dakota (783-625), 1983 (Box 188)
    - Sidewalk Clock in Front of Spy Hill Florist. Beacon, New York (NBF-163-179), 1963 (Box 188)
    - Steam Lighter Victor, New Harbor (EL-1167-1253), 1967 (Box 188)
    - Steamer Kinsman Independent Loading Wheat at Grain Elevator (685-1094), 1985 (Box 188)
    - Steamer J.B. Ford On Lake Michigan, approaching Waukegan, Illinois (1085-31), 1985 (Box 188)
    - Steamer Lone Star on Mississippi River, Version No. 4. On Mississippi River, Davenport, Iowa (964-181), 1964 (Box 188)
    - Storm. Norway Township, Humboldt County, Iowa (611-349), 2011 (Box 188)
    - Street and Grain Elevator, Detail. Burlington, Colorado (610-959), 2010 (Box 188)
    - Sweet Shop. Versailles, Ohio (605-1242), 2005 (Box 188)
    - Tractor, Goldsmith Farm. Near Tipton, Cedar County, Iowa (686-1581), 1986 (Box 188)
    - Two Bridges Across East Channel of Narragansett Bay, Looking from Jamestown Island, Jamestown Verrazano Bridge (right) (798-644), 1998 (Box 188)
    - Union Pacific Railroad Grade Crossing, Clare, Humboldt County Iowa (611-182), 2011 (Box 188)
    - Upper Deck Saloon, Ferryboat Pocono, Erie-Lackawanna Railroad (EL-467-31), 1967 (Box 188)
    - Walter Kowalik, Fireman, and Fireman Jim Brown In firehold of F/B Elmira, Hoboken Ferry Erie-Lackawanna County. Lackawanna County (EL-1167-191), 1967 (Box 188)
    - Wheat Harvest. Wilcox Township, Trego County, Kansas (610-1227), 2010 (Box 188)
  - June 2014 Acquisition
    Prints used by Plowden as examples for a class held at the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library on May 14-18, 2001, The Material Culture of American Photography, which featured Plowden, as well as Peter Palmquist and Richard Benson as a team of instructors.
    - Barn. Clair County, Michigan (975-1499), undated (Box 189)
    - Barn. LaGrange County, Indiana (969-906), undated (Box 189)
    - Barn. Near Guilford, Vermont (V-NH-865-326), undated (Box 189)
    - Boston Maine Railroad Whipple Murphy Truss Bridge, Connecticut River. Northampton, Massachusetts (GFB-68-3475), 1968 (Box 189)
    - Brick Arch Rings, Long Isalnd Railroad Bridge. Locust Valley, New York (173-257), 1974 (Box 189)
    - Bridge. Near Little Bouctouche River (GFP-69-1384), undated (Box 189)
    - Canadian Pacific Railway 4-6-2 #2408 (CPR 360), undated (Box 189)
    - Cape Creek Bridge. Lane County, Oregon (GFB 68-5102), 1974 (Box 189)
    - Cape Creek, Oregon, Route 101 CB McCullough, The Cape Creek Bridge. Lane County, Oregon (GFB 68-5103), undated (Box 189)
    - Church. Palm Springs, Arizona (678-297), undated (Box 189)
    - Church. Willimasville, Vermont (V-NH 1062-112), undated (Box 189)
    - Coal Loading Facility. Superior, Wisconsin (685-2243), 1985 (Box 189)
    - Golden Valley, North Dakota (GP-252), 1971 (Box 189)
    - Gotebo, Oklahoma (969-387), 1969 (Box 189)
    - Isabella County, Michigan (975-589), undated (Box 189)
    - Long Island Railroad. Count Salley, New York (273-257), 1974 (Box 189)
    - Louisville and Nashville Railroad Bridge. Ohio River, Cincinnati, Ohio (GFB-68-667), 1974 (Box 189)
    - Marion, Kansas (CP 623), undated (Box 189)
    - New Jersey Turnpike Bridge. Newark Bay, New Jersey (GFB-469-16), 1984 (Box 189)
    - New York City Farm. Jersey City, New York (1072-70), 1982 (Box 189)
    - Presque Isle Canal Dock. Toledo, Ohio (685-1460), 1985 (Box 189)
    - Roof of Cow Barn. Brookline, Vermont (V-765-135), 1965 (Box 189)
    - Side of Stone Barn. Wayne County, New York (WC 214), undated (Box 189)
    - Young's High Bridge. Near Tyrone, Kentucky (GFB 68-896), 1982 (Box 189)
- Papers, circa 1957-circa 2002; Series II; 39; 22.1 linear_feet
  Organized into four subseries: July 1995 Acquisition, April 1996 Acquisition, June 2002 Acquisition, and July 2003 Acquisition.
  Papers include correspondence, research notes, and drafts related to Plowden's photographs and publications, as well as copies of articles and clippings of works that used his images as illustrations, circa 1957-2002.
  - July 1995 Acquisition
    Organized under six headings that reflect Plowden's original arrangement of the material: Bridges: The Spans of North America; Multiple Publications; Industrial Landscape; Research Files; Small Town America; and United States Bicentennial, Abraham Lincoln, and Magazine Publications
    - Bridges: The Spans of North America
      Notes, research, and drafts related to David Plowden's Bridges: The Spans of North America (New York: Viking Press, 1974).
      - Wood, stone, iron, and concrete bridges, 36 folders (Box 190)
      - Steel I, Steel II, Steel III, miscellaneous, and bridge prints, 20 folders (Box 191)
      - Miscellaneous, 35 folders (Box 192)
      - Chapters 1-7 (Box 193)
    - Multiple Publications
      Notes, research, drafts, and proofs related to publications by Plowden, including The Hand of Man on America (Washington, D.C.: Smithsonian Institution Press; 1971), Floor of the Sky: the Great Plains (San Francisco: Sierra Club, 1972), Commonplace (New York: Sunrise Books, 1974), End of an Era: The Last of the Great Lakes Steamboats (New York: Norton, 1992) and Small Town America (New York: H.N. Abrams, 1994).
      - Hand of Man, Floor of the Sky, and Commonplace, 36 folders and 12 notebooks (Box 194)
      - Correspondence and publicity, 32 folders (Box 195)
      - Small Town America, Proofs, 10 folders (Box 196)
      - End of an Era: The Last of the Great Lakes Steamboats, Notes, research, and drafts, undated; 18 folders and 1 accordian file (Box 197)
    - Industrial Landscape
      Research material, drafts, and reviews related to Plowden's book, Industrial Landscape, (New York: Chicago Historical Society in association with Norton, 1985).
      - Notes, research, and drafts, 20 folders (Box 198)
      - Notes, research, drafts, and reviews, 50 folders (Box 199)
    - Research Files
      - Correspondence and research for writings and exhibits, 43 folders (Box 200)
      - Architectural magazines, 1963-1988; 59 magazines (Box 201)
      - Magazines and notes, 12 folders (Box 202)
      - Magazine publications, 1956-1968; 46 magazines (Box 203)
      - Collected photographs, 5 folders (Box 204)
      - Copy photographs related to publications by Plowden, 6 folders (Box 205)
      - Architectural blueprints, 6 folders and 1 roll (Box 206)
      - Newspaper articles, 5 folders and 1 roll (Box 207)
    - Small Town America
      - Galley proofs, 3 folders and 1 roll (Box 208)
    - United States Bicentennial, Abraham Lincoln, and Magazine Publications, 33 folders
      - Files, 1969-1992 (Box 209)
  - April 1996 Acquisition
    Purchased from David Plowden on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 1996.
    - Notes and research, 26 folders (Box 210)
    - Correspondence, drafts, and financial records, 10 folders (Box 211)
    - Drafts and notes, 36 folders and 1 accordian file (Box 212)
    - Drafts and notes, 16 folders (Box 213)
  - June 2002 Acquisition
    Organized under three headings that reflect Plowden's original arrangement of the material: Research and Correspondence Files, Bridges: The Spans of North America, and Proofs.
    Gift of David Plowden, 2002.
    - Research and Correspondence Files
      - Lakeshore Limited, 45 folders (Box 214)
      - Lakeshore Limited, 8 folders (Box 215)
      - Manuscript drafts and personal papers, 36 folders and 1 accordian file (Box 216)
      - Drafts of a memoir, 19 folders (Box 217)
      - Correspondence, 40 folders (Box 218)
      - Correspondence, 10 folders (Box 219)
      - Drafts and notes, 28 folders (Box 220)
      - Magazines relating to trains and photography, 13 Magazines (Box 221)
    - Bridges: The Spans of North America
      - Notes and drafts, 7 folders (Box 222)
      - Notes and drafts, 45 folders (Box 223)
    - Proofs
      Proofs for books by Plowden including Imprints: A Retrospective (Boston,(Massachusetts: Little Brown, 1997), and Bridges: the Span of North America.
      - Imprints: A Retrospective
        - Proofs, 5 folders (Box 224)
        - Proofs, 4 folders (Box 225)
      - Bridges: the Span of North America
        - Proofs, 3 folders (Box 226)
        - Proofs, 1 folder (Box 227)
  - July 2003 Acquisition
    This subseries consists of galley proofs for a reprinted edition Bridges: the Span of North America in 2002.
    - Bridges: the Span of North America, galley proofs, circa 2002; 26 folders (Box 228)